Curriculum Vitae

Pete Moore 2018-09-04

Introduction

I am currently available for Data Science work in Manchester and the North West.

I have more than two decades' experience in the data industry, and I love helping organisations get the most from their data. I advise on data strategy. I code at expert level in R, Python and SQL. I have hands-on experience with the following machine learning and deep learning algorithms and megthodologies: collaborative filters, association rules, k-means, restricted boltzmann machnes, convoluted neural networks. I have composed code using the following deep learning platforms: Tensorflow, Keras, DL4J. This list however is not exhaustive because I strongly believe that the problem picks the platform and I am always willing to enhance my skill set accordingly. I'm constantly learning and refining my skills and am currently studying for an MSc Data Science at the University of Dundee. My ethos is that it always starts with the data.

Experience

Founder, Look at your Data Ltd - Jan 2017 - Dec 2018

Look at your Data delivered GDPR training to medium-sized groups of varied backgrounds, organisations and technical abilities.

Big learns:building a product, engaging an audience, how to listen.

Non-executive Director, ManchesterSQL - Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

I was an inaugural member of Manchester SQL, a not-for-profit that organised the annual SQL Saturday conference and the monthly SQL Server User Group.

IT Director, Evolution Recruitment Solutions – Sep 2004 - Dec 2016

For twelve years I worked for the Evolution Group. It was eight people when I started. By the time I left it was an internaional group of six companies. I sat on the board of all. Evolution is the only recruitment business of its size to be recognised as Microsoft Gold Partners.

It all begins with the data. Evolution had lots of it and a SQL Server. What's more they had ambition. If that SQL Server was the Millennium Falcon, then I was hired to be R2D2. Initially, I was on a three-month contract to deduplicate the data, soon afterwards I was coding fuzzy matching, proto-Machine Learning and business critical matching algorithms.

IT Director, Evolution Recruitment Solutions – Jan 2012 - Dec 2016

I joined the board of Evolution in 2012 and the full board one year later. The first person ever to break into the inner circle having been a junior in the company. I was a manager before this role, but I learned about management during it.

- Data warehouse
- Virtualised Infrastructure

- Key achievements:
- A happy IT team who worked well together and every member of whom I remain proud of
- Microsoft Gold Partners
- Introduction of Kanban (pan-organisation)
- Best in class recruitment technology
- MI as a habit

Big learns:communicating cross-enterprise, selling achievements of my team, how to be on a board, how to be a brand ambassador.

IT Manager, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Jan 2007 - Dec 2011

After two years at Evolution my job title changed from Data- to IT- Manager. My main passion remained data, but the still small business need a comprehensive function and I was the obvious candidate to lead it.

This period began with the great recession, moved to a period of rapid UK-based expansion and culminated in a small single-brand, single-office, single-country, single-language company, to a multi-national, multiple brand enterprise.

- Migration from SQL Server 2000 to SQL Server 2008.
- MI as standard.
- Build and A/B testing of commercial websites.
- Key achievements:
- Establishment of scalable helpdesk function with replicable job units.
- Establishment of Data Management function.
- Pioneering of Database as a Service model (on SQL Server 2008) to allow a franchise-based business model.

Big learns:communication to board, educational platform for new hires, mail server management, active directory management, working in a recession.

Data Manager, Evolution Recruitment Solutions - Sep 2004 - Dec 2006

My initial role at Evolution started when I was younger and more audacious. "If you can say it, I can code it" were the exact words that left my mouth. Whilst I never quite regretted them, it led to some interesting projects. Simply, no idea was too big and the projects we worked on then would one day be called "Data Science".

- Complex algorithms for CV matching and importing in SQL Server VB.Net and VB6.
- Wages automation in SQL Server and classic ASP.
- Elementary machine learning for email analysis.
- Establishment of Data Team plus basic support infrastructure.
- Introduction of per-consultant MI using SQL Server and ASP.

Big learns: interaction with software house, recruitment industry.

Senior Data Manager, LBM - Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

LBM used data to drive direct marketing campaigns in the B2B sector.

Senior Data Manager, LBM - Aug 2002 - Oct 2003

LBM demanded and if you didn't deliver you were out. I was in charge of the most important database in the company. Achieving this meant taking SQL Server and knowing the product inside out; going from apprentice to subject matter expert. If this seems unreasonable: it was. I didn't enjoy working at LBM, but I did learn a lot.

Big learns:interviewing, how to manage a person, coping with hostility, communication to clients, communication to management, B2B direct marketing industry.

Data Specialist, Inter • Act Systems - Aug 1999 - Apr 2002

Inter • Act leveraged EPOS data to provide B2C offers through kiosk technology.

Business Applications Specialist, Inter • Act Systems - Apr 2001 - Apr 2002

Introduction to OLAP, ROLAP, Set-based programming using Business Objects Software.

Data Analyst, Inter • Act Systems – Aug 1999 - Apr 2000

Providing, interpreting and automating reports for sales teams.

Big learns: writing reports for sales teams, communicating data analysis, Excel macro writing, FMCG industry

Hobbies

In a lifetime of travel, I have scaled many of Europe's highest peaks, hiked fifty miles in a day for charity, and I have visited every US state apart from Hawaii. I even wrote a (bad) book about the latter.

I follow football, cricket, baseball and NFL. Sometimes to a level bordering on excessive. Ditto rock music, popular science and computing. I am genuinely passionate about my muse and don't differentiate studying about data from reading for pleasure.

In my spare time I like to perform stand-up and improv.

Public speaking

As one who spends their spare time performing improve and stand-up comedy, it stands to reason that I like public speaking.

As a data professional I am fortunate enough to get invited to speak in locations as far afield as Ljubljana, Copenhagen but mostly Manchester. I have spoken in public on the facets of data that mean most to me: how to code well, how to communicate data by visualisation, to your boss and, fundamentally, how to keep this ethical.

Volunteering

In addition to speaking at numerous events to promote the virtues of using data correctly, I have volunteered for the following organisations:

Microsoft (PASS Chapter) - 2016-2017

Co-leader

Organise the monthly user group

 $Manchester \ SQL-2016-2017$

Co-organiser

Organise the annual SQL Saturday conference (300 attendees)

FC United - 2005-9999

Co-owner

Take football back

Summer work

I need to work, and this has always been true. I include my late-nineties Summer works because they taught me so much. (If you want to know just how much then click the links)

Rides Assistant, Santa Cruz Beach Boardwalk - Jun 1998 - Sep 1998

Rides assistant

Big learns:Manage up

Games Assistant, Family Kingdom Amusement Park – Jun 1997 - Sep 1997

Games assistant

Big learns:Handle rednecks

Data Analyst, John Dickinson Stationery – Jun 1996 - Sep 1996

Commercial Analyst

Big learns:Make money from data

Assistant Project Manager, Nat West - Jun 1995 - Sep 1995

Assistant Project Manager

Big learns:Be in an office

Education

Education is important to me and I hope never to stop learning.

Studying Data Science has taught me the why behind the what of the data things I do. Study has coalesced disparate tasks into a body of knowledge as opposed to a bag of tricks. (It has defnitely taught me there is no such thing as genius!)

Finally, my A-level results, of which I emaiproud.

MSc Data Science, University of Dundee - Jan 2017 - Jan 2019

MSc Data Science - Postgraduate Masters

Distinction (expected)

MSci Mathematical Physics, University of Nottingham - Oct 1995 - Jun 1999

MSci Mathematical Physics - Undergraduate Masters

2:1 (Hons)

A-levels, Longdean School – Sep 1993 - Jun 1995

Physics - S-Level

Distinction

Geography - A-Level

Α

Maths - A-Level

Α

Physics - A-Level

Α

Further Maths - A-Level

В

CV edition information (internal use only)

Data Scientist CV issue 2(2) for Peter Moore